I couldn't sleep the night before my
first transformation I either feel like
I'm about to explode there's nothing to
be scared of you'll be right here with
us
I promise that I keep I'll never share
to my grave
being hard the 30 hearted mystic
creatures
who these basil
the Isle of Lindisfarne as I express in
my book resources and religion on
medieval Lindisfarne has always been a
sanctuary and practically safe haven as
it is cut off from the outside world for
most of the day which is why we have
timed our visits so
Katrine it what's wrong max nothing I'm
six I ever how's everyone doing when we
get back I'm gonna just hatched some
chicks they are so fluffy you have to
see sorry shad
oh damn I'm a tease oh yeah Mama's
making a family tree finding out about
Rhydian side of the family all the black
sheep ways yeah come on everyone top top
we go Lindisfarne castle was built
around 15 1550 using stones from the
abandoned monastery which may explain
why the castle is haunted what imagine
you're a Lindisfarne armed men arrive
you go you want inside the monastery a
place of safety no one would dare you
lock yourself in
have to get out there not in the cellars
not looking too good now is it it's
gonna be horrible I don't know how my
parents do it how are we gonna do it
you're up here you to miss the best bit
monks are getting the heads chopped off
it was brilliant ah there you are oh
dear
rather high up here are we um I've got a
bit carried away down there I'm sorry it
wasn't you miss claustrophobia I
understand that the imagination is far
more powerful than the logical brain we
know there's no danger stood on a roof
or in a crowded room but I'm still so
what do I do miss and you need to get in
some place and instinct Olly it's too
scary to even try if I knew the answer
to that Maddie I would feel a lot better
stood on this roof see you downstairs
when you're ready didn't know
claustrophobia was catch in okay people
the questions cover the castle the lime
kills together with the church and the
Priory so for those of you who have been
paying attention this should be very
easy and there is a prize for the most
correct answers and remember to be back
at the minibus by five o'clock without
fail or we will miss the time
right well we know questions 12 to 15 so
we just need to answer three questions
in the village to in the line kill all
in the Priory two on the beach okay then
you to take the church in a village and
we'll do the rest something where to you
and I'm sorry
Jeffers doesn't care how we get the
answers as long as we go good one and
Apple finish fast enough
well I've totally gone for ice cream oh
yeah brilliant right so we'll meet you
both with the prior relate
Suvir brilliant place to spend for me
yeah yeah on an island
what could be safer running on the
beaches playing in the ruins would be
amazing so let's do it
brilliant a court your parents are
expecting this one here to share their
cozy little den this is my first
transformation I wanna be with my family
and you promised you'd spend full moon
with her so there's nothing else to talk
about is there
idiots ahoy we're doing Jimmy
stealing the crabs lunch money I haven't
got any they're feeling the pinch
I tell you what I set up your worksheet
answers help yourself
it's blank
go fetch Luke boy on your way well I'm
gonna get it leak boy ha ha good for
Jimmy to choose Mike what's he going up
and ask I'm gonna watch
come on Rhydian we don't have time today
you might have broken up on just talk
the hell away leave are you okay
where does it hurt mind call surprise
surprise no Rhydian
no Maddy probably smooching on the beeps
um right we have two competing theories
one they're dating and two she's yeah
what we need is evidence from now on we
stick to them like glue on the bus at
school after school every way they'd go
we're there I either will find 11 before
they gets offered up with us they have
to start on agreed you need to get to
the bus route and still get off the
island and leave you on your own I won't
be on my own
one of the teachers will stay with me
the other one will get you home before
the moon rises
you can't transform with a teacher
staying with you I'll be fine just get
off the Arlen while you still can
I'm not going anywhere I'm gonna make
sure you get through those muddy if you
want to transform with your parents you
have to go now I can't leave you here
Rhydian sir everyone on the coast
Tom Shannon sit down finish let mr.
Jeffries deal with it Maddy I'm fine go
she has to go home sir all right I don't
why we're all gonna go home tonight
don't you worry about that okay it
doesn't appear to me broken dinner take
his other one but the tide sir it's all
right it's all gonna be back at the bus
15 minutes early we hurry Apple still
making it
Maddy come on okay all right okay
all right don't panic okay
you okay you all right injury in get us
moving
all right
everyone calm down next little tight
midnight nowhere
what I quiet please
I'm spoken to the head teacher we've
taken the decision that we're gonna stay
here overnight I'm gonna go back first
thing in the morning
luckily the hotel can squeeze us all in
but it's gonna be three or four to a
room gather up your things please or
allocate your room operation to stick
like glue share right we've lost Maddy
already radiant can't walk was stuck on
an island and we best mate already
thinks I'm the beast up stoney retro
earth look don't panic Rhydian I'll be
fine once he transforms that the full
moon heals almost anything in a
wolfblood but you both have to be out of
the village by 8:30
we should never come here give
everything to be back at home maybe we
could get to you by boat how would you
explain that to the teachers you won't
get here by 8:30 and I didn't hardly a
pause listen buddy you're on video no
good after think your way out of this
the two of you you're on your own now
cut but what if you do make sure you get
out of the village in time
exactly luxurious but you can't manage
the stairs
I'll be fine miss Thanks private room
job ma'am can I uh give you an with that
yeah
cool right thank your girls
so I'll go in there
oh no that's reserved for her I love I
guess laughter going with the keys
oh look its radiance girlfriend I'm not
his girl fell because he was sure enough
to you which means it's your fault we're
struggling the old Lindisfarne with no
pj nor cleanses and not hey underwear
it's not much agree it's allergy girl
hey Mouse Samson screams you know I
think we should complain poor animals
Maddie where have you been
couldn't get rid of Shannon yeah Tom was
in here being on matey
and there's something sup how are you
gonna get out without people missing you
shun will think I'm with the three kids
I'll tell the three kids I've moved back
in it's Shannon's room she'll think with
them they'll think I'm with her symbols
and then I'll help get you up help me
I'm awake yeah I really wouldn't worry
about that
mom says it'll heal once you transform
we both need to get out the village by
8:30 okay she leaves separately to meet
the boat sheds okay look he'll be okay
I've done this loads of times twice okay
twice there'll be all remedy I'll look
after you
the ghost dog Lindisfarne only last year
a young couple wandering near
Lindisfarne castle came across the
entrance to the abandoned line inside
they heard a string on earth thinking it
was a dog that had got trapped in one of
the tunnels foolishly went inside to
investigate little did they know they
were entering the lair of the ghost
white dog or Linda's Swan and they were
never going to come out well the next
day their friends went in search of them
but the couple had disappeared all they
found were the mobile phones on one was
a recording a terrible snarling and
screams as if the couple had been
attacked by some sort of monster
officially the case remains uncertain
unofficially they blame the white dog of
Linda's mom all right who's got another
good I'm just going to vote off me -
what's wrong with you nothing well
you've been following around like James
Bond on a mission just hanging out
it's what mates do if you're avoiding me
friend you just back off and give us
some space no cleanser no toner my
skin's gonna end up worse than yours
where you going
I'm moving to Shannon through good
riddance
don't you geek in a barroom anyway
oh no good convention
she's moved into your room lamebrain no
she hasn't
yeah some wet tongue so I was just going
Maddie's disappeared her guess what when
he is liked it a person I'm gonna find
him and I'm gonna get some answers
come on Tony yes
you
you know that go story mr. Chi sterile
told I don't think that was a ghost
it's a full moon mady's changed you
kidding you got to be kidding right
shun she's on the beach let's go
missile I'm kill the mortgage lime kills
the white dog from Linda's farmland
kills we've gotta now come on look see
there's nothing here great can we go out
poor prince
come on Tom this is a good idea don't be
such a baby it's cold and dark look we
need to go there's nothing here
this way
what was that relax we've gotten out
please honest go
there's nothing here
it's not noise
he's the ghost dog has no such thing as
ghosts what do you think lock to save a
Shan
it was Maddie huh you saw it right
anyone knocking back in 30 seconds yes
extra homework where were you last night
well Shannon has the site you were there
Tom you know I'm right
right about what Maddie was out all
night
and you went with her we followed the
sound of the howling to the Limekiln and
there was something there we think you
think I think Maddie changed last night
became something else and you know about
her what are you talking about something
knock Tom over it wasn't human
well it could have been a dog a fox or
could've been a bunch of local kids who
thought you were that Ghost Dog it could
have been anything
and where was Maddie all night well I've
got an idea let's ask her fine
open up call me loser I'm coming in no
have any makeup on where's Maddie draw
nice colors haven't seen her all night
boys get them out oh oh you are well you
didn't think I was gonna share with them
did you
I sneaked downstairs spent the night on
the silver where'd you go Rhydian last
night me and Rhydian went on a walk his
leg is hurting
I can smell bacon
dan you all want to come to breakfast me
I could eat a whole pig
I'm sweet okay come on sir hmm you never
gave out the prize for the worksheet
that's a very good point Jenny I'll tell
you one let's call it a draw everybody
wins
take one hand them out
let's save one for misfits Dale yeah
they're so going up they're lying
they have to be you know there was
something up there uh radium was right
reads it's a straighter ha it was dark
all those ghost stories use your Occam's
razor thing like simplest explanation
wins reading disappeared Maddy
disappeared I date it simple as
explanation right maybe that was amazing
I so get it now being a wolf that's
gonna be so great come on it
you